cv.md 12/30/2021

## **Marcel Ochs**

### Software Engineer

E-Mail: marcel@ochs.rocks Github: github.com/CashWasabi

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/marcel-ochs-812582139/

#### **SKILLS**

I am a passionate developer. At my last jobs I worked with Flask, FastAPI, AWS, Jenkins (CI/CD) MySQL, PostGresSQL, MongoDB, Redis, PyTest, Grafana, Sentry, Git and several other tools, libs and frameworks. I also recently started looking into Django for side projects. My preferred OS currently is Manjaro Linux. I know my way around microservices or monolithic architectures and I am not afraid of working on architectural solutions that solve problems.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Vimcar GmbH, Berlin (Germany) - Python Backend Developer

(January 2019 - Juli 2021)

- Microservices
- AWS Cloud
- · Data analysis and workflow monitoring

Address-Base GmbH & Co. KG, Karlsruhe (Germany) - Python Backend Developer

(May 2015 - September 2018)

- · Web crawlers
- CRUD and Rest-APIs
- Data improvement and normalisation (ETL)
- · Data analysis and workflow monitoring

Virtual7 GmbH, Karlsruhe (Germany) - Apprentice

(May 2012 - May 2015)

- Deployment automatisation
- Data transformation (ETL)

cv.md 12/30/2021

## SIDE PROJECTS

- Game Development (Rust Bevy)
- Generative Art (Rust Nannou)
- Trading Bot for Cryptocurrency Exchanges

# **Favourite Languages**

- Rust
- Python
- JavaScript

#### **LANGUAGES**

- English (fluet)
- German (native)

### **EDUCATION**

Heinrich-Hertz Schule, Karlsruhe (Germany)

(September 2012 - May 2015)

• IT Specialist

Wilhelm-Röpke Schule, Ettlingen (Germany)

(September 2007 - May 2012)

• Fachhochschulreife